azmind.com 2019-02-04

# Privacy Policy | AZMIND

At azmind.com (this site) we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here you can see what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit this site, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

### Who we are

Our website address is: https://azmind.com. This site is run by Anli Zaimi a web designer and developer based in Turin, Italy. You can conact us at **contact.azmind@gmail.com**.

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

We do not collect your email address from the comments form for use in any email list, such as a newsletter or marketing email list. We also never sell email addresses to third parties.

#### Media

Users are not able to upload images or other media files to this website.

#### Contact forms

This website does not have contact forms. You can contact us using the email address above.

#### Email newsletter

We have an email newsletter in this site where we send you updates when we release new themes, tutorials, freebies or articles. We also send freebies available only to email subscribers. You are free to subscribe to the newsletter or not.

When you subscribe, we save your email address and IP (internet protocol) address. You can see, edit and/or delete all this data from the links at the bottom of each email we send you, or by contacting us at the email address above.

We also collect view and click tracking for the newsletters we send, to learn what our users like more. You can edit or disable view and click tracking from the “Preferences” link at the bottom of each email we send you, or by contacting us at the email address above.

In any case, we don’t sell or share this data.

We use a third party service to store this data and to send the newsletters. The service is “Mad Mimi” and their privacy policy can be found [on their site](https://madmimi.com/).

#### Easy Digital Downloads (for purchases on this site)

We may use a plugin called “Easy Digital Downloads” if/when we sell something (themes, templates) directly from this site. During the purchase, we save your name, email address, location and traffic data (IP address, browser type), and any other details requested only for the purpose of processing your order.

We never sell or share this data.

You can request to see, edit and/or delete this data by contacting us at this email address: contact.azmind@gmail.com.

#### Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files includes your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider), the browser you used to visit our site (Internet Explorer, Chrome, etc.), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

#### Cookies

Here is our [Cookie policy](https://azmind.com/cookie-policy/).

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Analytics

As you use this site, we use automatic data collection technology (Google Analytics) to collect certain information about your device, browsing actions, and patterns. This generally includes information about where you are, how you use our website, and any communications between your computer and this site. Among other things, we will collect data about the type of computer you use, your Internet connection, your IP address, your operating system, and your browser type.

We collect this data for statistical purposes and we don’t collect personal information. The purpose of this data is to improve our site and offerings.

If you want to opt out of Google Analytics so that none of your personal information is collected and stored by Google Analytics, you can [download and install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). For more information on how Google collects and uses your data, you can [see the Google Privacy Policy here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

### Who we share your data with

We don’t sell or share your data with anyone. As we said above, we use a third party service called “Mad Mimi” for the email newsletter, if you voluntarily subscribed for our email newsletter. Read above to learn more.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

Users can’t register on our website.

If you subscribe to our newsletter, we retain the data indefinitely, or at least until you modify or delete them (unsubscribe from the newsletter).

If you make a purchase directly on this site, we retain the data indefinitely, or at least until you modify or delete it.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments or have subscribed to our email newsletter, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

You can make your requests by contacting us at this email address: contact.azmind@gmail.com.

For the email newsletter you can modify or delete your data from the links at the bottom of each email we send you, or by contacting us at the email address above.

If you make a purchase directly on this site, you can modify or delete your data by contacting us at the email address above.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments are checked through an automated spam detection service called Akismet by Automattic Inc. Akismet collects information about visitors who comment on sites that use the Akismet anti-spam service. The information Akismet collects typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself). You can see [Akismet’s privacy policy here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

For the email newsletter we use a third party service to store the users’ data (email and IP) and to send the newsletters. The service is called “Mad Mimi” and their privacy policy can be found [on their site](https://madmimi.com/).

### Our contact information

For questions about your data and how we use it, you can contact us at **contact.azmind@gmail.com**. You can also email us here if you want an extract of all your personal information stored on this website or to request that we delete all of your information stored on this website.

### Additional information

#### How we protect your data

We use HTTP Secure (HTTPS) for secure communication between you and this site. You can [read more about HTTPS here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS).

We never sell or share your data.

————–

Last Edited on May 29, 2018
